(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.1",
"generated_at": "2026-06-17T11:46:21.818998",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Step Into Dreams
ホロライブに入る!!
I will join Hololive!!
碧青
Gunjou (Ultramarine)
嗚呼、いつもの様に
Ah, as always...
過ぎる日々にあくびが出る
I yawn at the passing days.
さんざめく夜、越え、今日も
Crossing the bustling night, today again,
渋谷の街に朝が降る
morning descends on the streets of Shibuya.
どこか虚しいような
A somewhat empty feeling...
そんな気持ち
such a feeling.
つまらないな、でもそれでいい規定
It's so boring, but that's okay.
そんなもんさ、これでいい
That's just how it is, this is fine.
知らず知らず隠してた本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
Let your true voice, which you unknowingly hid, resonate, look.
見ないフリしていても確かにそこにある
Even if you pretend not to see it, it is definitely there.
感じたままに描く
Draw exactly as you feel
自分で選んだその色で
with the colors you chose yourself.
眠い空気纏う朝に
On a morning wrapped in sleepy air,
訪れた青い世界
a blue world has visited.
好きなものを好きだと言う
To say I love what I love,
怖くて仕方ないけど
even though I'm unbearably scared...
本当の自分
I felt like my true self
嗚呼、手を伸ばせば伸ばすほどに
Ah, the more I reach my hand out,
遠くへゆく
the further away it goes.
思うようにいかない、今日も
Things don't go as planned, and today again,
また慌ただしくもがいてる
I struggle busily once more.
悔しい気持ちもただ情けなくて
This frustrating feeling is just so pathetic
涙が出る
that tears begin to fall.
踏み込むほど苦しくなる
The further I step in, the more painful it gets,
痛くもなる
and it even starts to hurt.
感じたままに進む
Proceed exactly as you feel
自分で選んだこの道を
on this path you chose yourself.
重いまぶた擦る夜に
On a night rubbing heavy eyelids,
しがみついた青い誓い
I clung onto that blue vow.
好きなことを続けること
Continuing to do what you love
それは「楽しい」だけじゃない
is not just about it being 'fun'.
本当にできる？ 不安になるけど
Can I really do it? I get anxious, but...
自信がないから描いてきたんだよ
because I lacked confidence, I kept on drawing.
あぁ 何回でも ほら何回でも
Ah, no matter how many times, look, no matter how many times
積み上げてきたことが武器になる
everything I've built up will become my weapon
周りを見たって 誰と比べたって
Even if I look around, even if I compare myself to anyone
僕にしかできないことはなんだ
what is it that only I can do?
今でも自信なんか無い それでも
Even now, I have no confidence, but still...
感じたことない気持ち
A feeling I've never felt before
知らずにいた想い
thoughts I never knew I had
あの日の踏み出して 初めて感じた
Taking that step that day, and for the first time feeling...
この痛みも全部
even all of this pain
好きなものと向き合うことで
By facing what I love
触れたまだ小さな光
I touched a still tiny light
大丈夫 行こう あとは楽しむだけだ
It's alright, let's go, all that's left is to enjoy it
あぁ 全てを懸けて描く
Ah, risking everything to paint
自分にしか出せない色で
with colors only I can create
朝も夜も走り続け
Running through morning and night
見つけ出した青い光
the blue light I've found
好きなものと向き合うこと
Facing what I love
今だって怖いことだけど
is still scary even now
もう今はあの日の透明な僕じゃない
But I am no longer the transparent me of that day
ありのままの かけがえのない僕だ
I am who I am, irreplaceable
知らず知らず隠していた
Without realizing, I had hidden
本当の声を響かせてよ ほら
Let your true voice ring out, look!
見ないフリしていったって
Even if you pretend not to see it
確かにそこに今もそこにあるよ
It's surely there, even now, it's right there
知らず知らず隠していた
Without realizing, I had hidden
本当の声を響かせてよ さあ
Let your true voice ring out, come on!
見ないフリしていったって
Even if you pretend not to see it
確かにそこに君の中に
It's surely there, inside of you
ダメダメダメ脳みその中からやめろ、バカ、たわけ、モラリティ
No, no, no! Screaming from inside my brain, 'Stop it, idiot, fool, morality!'
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン あんぽんたんラブとトキメキ
Darlin', baby, darlin', simpleton love and heartbeat
浮き足立つフィロソフィー
An unstable philosophy
死ぬほど可愛い 上目遣い
Deadly cute upturned eyes
何が司法に触れるくらい
What's bordering on breaking the law?
ばらまく惨事 気づけば当事
Scattered disaster, before I knew it, I'm involved
この世に生まれた君が悪い
Born into this world, it's your fault
やたらと深刻 恋患い
Incredibly serious lovesickness
バラバラになる頭とこの身体
My head and body are falling apart
けど脈あり？ 愛ラブユー 聞かせてアイ、アイ
But is there a pulse? 'I love you', let me hear 'I'
アイ、アイ、アイ、アイリスアウト
I- I- I- Iris out
誰？ 誰？ 誰？ 誰？
Who? Who? Who? Who?
控えめに言っても勝ち目ない
Even to put it mildly, there's no chance of winning
君だけルールは適用外
For you alone, the rules don't apply
狂うしかない 勝負は大敗
I have no choice but to go crazy, this match is a crushing defeat
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラ
The Avada Kedavra you shot with a smile
平伏してても申し訳ないな
Even if I bow down, I feel no regret
手を差し出して 連れ出して
Reach out your hand, take me away
ここが弱点？
Is this the weak spot?
死ぬほど可愛い 上目遣い
Deadly cute upturned eyes
何が司法に触れるくらい
What's bordering on breaking the law?
ばらまく惨事 気づけば当事
Scattered disaster, before I knew it, I'm involved
この世に生まれた君が悪い
Born into this world, it's your fault
パチモンでもいい なんでもいい
Even a knockoff is fine, anything is fine
今君と紡いでる すべてが欲しい
I want everything that we are spinning together now
けど脈あり？ 愛ラブユー 聞かせてアイ
But is there a pulse? 'I love you', let me hear 'I'
アイ、アイ、アイ、アイリスアウト
I- I- I- Iris out
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What's to be done? What to do with this feeling?
あばらの奥のざわめきが 溶けてケモノになりそう
The rustling deep within my ribs seems to melt and turn me into a beast
どっかバグっちゃって 溺れていくのさ
Something bugged out, drowning
今 この世で君だけが 正解
Right now, in this world, only you are the correct answer
誰？ 誰？ 誰？ 誰？
Who? Who? Who? Who?
出張中もスマホの充電足りてる？
Is your phone fully charged even while on business trips?
ホロライブDEV_IS FLOW GLOWの異能担当、水谷ちよでーす！
From Hololive DEV_IS, FLOW GLOW's supernatural representative, Mizutani Chiyo here!
ということで、ステップ・イントゥ・ドリームス始まりましたー！イェーイ！
And with that, "Step into Dreams" has begun! Yay!
今回はですね、オープニングにもあった通り
This time, as you saw in the opening,
夢だったホロライブに入って、夢だった初めてのソロ...
joining Hololive, which was my dream, and having my very first solo...
生誕ライブ、それでぃ、いえーい！
Birthday Live! Here we go, YAY!
ちょっとめちゃめちゃに緊張しているんですけれども、
I'm super, super nervous right now, but...
どうだった？群青のアイリスアウト。コメント欄どうだった？
How was it? Gunjou no Iris Out! How was the comment section?
かっこよかった？
Was it cool?
かっこよかったって、きっと、まあこの後流れるんだろうな。
I'm sure comments saying 'it was cool' will flow by after this.
かっこよかっただろ？
It was cool, wasn't it?
いっぱい褒めてください！
Please shower me with compliments!
今回はですね、タイトルにもある通り...
This time, just as the title says...
もうステップが、はちゃめちゃに、もう...
The steps are just super...
ステップがステップが、はちゃめちゃに多かったりですね、
...there are just so many crazy steps,
あとは、やったことのないジャンルのダンスにも
and I'm also challenging dance genres...
挑戦しちゃったりしていますので、お楽しみに！
...I've never done before, so look forward to it!
ハッシュタグは、こちらにある...
The hashtag is...
ハッシュタグ水宮すう生誕祭2026です！
...#MizumiyaSuuBirthdayFestival2026!
スクショとか、感想とか...
Screenshots, impressions...
たくさんポストしてくれると、嬉しいです！
...I'd be so happy if you posted lots of them!
目指せトレンド！
Aim for trending!
みんな、いっぱい呟いてね！
Everyone, tweet a lot!
この後はですね、ゲストパートにも
After this, I'm planning to move on...
行きたいと思っているのですが、
...to the guest part, but...
なんと、お祝いの映像が届いているみたいなので、
It looks like some congratulatory video messages...
見てみましょう！
...have arrived, so let's watch them!
こっちかな？よし。なんだなんだ？
Is it over here? Okay. What is it, what is it?
きみを笑顔にご案内、ラフの観光大使で
Guiding you to a smile, Raft's Tourism Ambassador,
にじさんじ所属、彩影の末っ子、シガリコだよ！
Nijisanji member and youngest sibling of Ayakiki, Shigariko here!
水宮ー！お誕生日おめでとう！ / リコー！ありがとう！
Mizumiya! Happy birthday! / Riko! Thank you!
きっと今、水宮は最高のライブを
I'm sure Mizumiya is having the best live show...
していることでしょう。本当におめでとう！
...right now. Truly, happy birthday!
本当はね、現地で直接お祝いがしたかったんですけど、
Honestly, I wanted to celebrate in person, but...
どうしてもスケジュールが合わないということで、
our schedules just didn't work out,,og:
お祝いのメッセージ動画を送らせていただいております。
so I'm sending this congratulatory message video!
水宮とはね、ロロメロとしてたくさんコラボして、
We've collaborated a lot as Roromero,
プライベートとかでもテーマパーク行ったり、映画行ったり、
and privately gone to theme parks and movies,
月一でお泊まりするくらい仲良くさせてもらってて、
and we're close enough to have monthly sleepovers.
本当にいつもありがとう！
Thank you so much for everything, always!
事務所が違うのにこんなに仲良くなれるなんて、
I'm so happy we can be this close...
めっちゃ嬉しいし、いつも水宮に元気もらって、
...even though we're from different agencies..
支えてもらんでます。
I'm always energized and supported by you.
これからもずっと友達！
Let's be friends forever!
色々遊んで、いっぱい楽しいことしていこうね。大好きだよ！
Let's hang out and do lots of fun things together. I love you!
それでは、シガリコでした！
And with that, this was Shigariko!
この後もライブ楽しんでね、頑張れー！
Enjoy the rest of the live show, you've got this!
うわああああ！
Uwaaaa!
ということで、シガリコからメッセージが届きました！
And that was a message from Shigariko!
ありがとう、シガリコ！こっちにいるかな？ありがとうシガリコー！
Thank you, Shigariko! Are you on this side? Thank you, Shigariko!
いや、そう、今回はですね、ちょっとスケジュールが合わなくて、
Yeah, so, our schedules didn't align this time,
リコの3Dには呼んでもらって一緒に踊ったんですけど、
but she invited me to her 3D and we danced together.
すうのライブでは今回は踊れなかったけど、いつか一緒にまた踊ろうな！
We couldn't dance together at my live this time, but let's dance again someday!
ありがとうね、リコ！水宮、頑張るよ！
Thank you, Riko! Mizumiya is going to do her best!
応援してもらったし、ちょっと次の曲にいこうかな？
Since I got cheered on, I'll move to the next song!
次はゲストパートだから、誰が来るのかな？
Next is the guest part, so I wonder who's coming?
この後も、まだまだ続きます！
There's still a lot more to come after this!
そしてなんか告知もあるかもしれないので、
And there might even be some announcements,
最後まで楽しんでね！
so please enjoy until the very end!
昔々の そのまた昔 とある貴族の 仲良しな兄弟
Long, long ago, in a time even further back / There lived a pair of noble siblings who were close friends
（以下略）
(and so on...)
「ちゃんとやれ！」
"Do it properly!"
じいやが呼ぶ 席につけ よーいどん！
The butler calls, take your seats, ready, set, go!
ナイフとフォークで 応戦いたしますの
With knife and fork, I shall offer my counterattack
だって僕らは ブルジョアの 立派な立派な 貴族様なんですですの
Because we are splendid, splendid / bourgeois nobles, you see
はーい はーい はい はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
花丸よくできました☆
Well done, good job☆
あ゙ーむかつくぜ！まーぢむかつくぜ！
Ah, it makes me mad! It really makes me mad!
僕に向かって減らず口なんざ
Spouting backtalk like that to me!
とっておきを君に見舞え
I'll show you something special!
報復制裁 挑発しちゃって
Retaliation, provocation, you've done it!
意地悪して一枚上
Playing dirty, I'm one step ahead!
チャンスは貰ってくスタンスで
I'm taking the chance with this stance!
痛恨ミス あちゃっちゃー
A fatal mistake, oops!
おあいにく様だね 君の負け
It's a pity, but it's your defeat!
(イェス！)
Yes!
だけど君 君だけが
But you, only you...
せいっ やぁっ とぉっ やぁっ うっ うっ やぁっ はっ
Seiya! To, ya, u, u, ya, a, ha!
僕に似合いのライバル
Are a rival suited for me!
せいっ やぁっ とぉっ やぁっ うっ とぉっ やぁっ はっ
Seiya! To, ya, u, to, ya, a, ha!
落ちるのも 凹んでるのも
Falling down, feeling depressed...
うっ はっ せいっ やぁっ やぁっ せいっ はっ
U, ha, seiya! Ya, sei, ha!
調子狂わされるから
Because you throw off my rhythm!
今宵もてめぇとやいやいやいやい
Tonight, I'll argue with you again, yai yai yai!
ハイ決定！イェーイ！
And it's decided! Yay!
あ゙ーむかつくぜ！まーぢむかつくぜ！
Ah, it makes me mad! It really makes me mad!
憎まれ口もお口をチャック
Shut your hateful mouth up!
閧の声ゴングを鳴らせ
Sound the trumpet of war, ring the gong!
次世代エンペラーはこの俺だ
The next-gen emperor is... this me!
悪戯して 悪ノリして
Playing pranks, egging each other on!
ほら ほら 煽ってくStyleで
Look, look, with an escalating style!
一から百いただきます
Taking everything from one to a hundred!
毎度ありがとうで 君のま…
Thanks for your patronage, your de...
まさかの引き分け？
Wait, it's a draw?!
えーっ？！
Eh?!
リードコントロール
[Title: Lead Control]
この頃 君が纏う 「躾直し」の季節の匂い
The scent of the season of "re-education" you're wrapped in lately...
強かな佇まいの割に脆い ソコに触れるの
Touching the fragile spot despite your tough exterior.
あぁ 怒らないで darling！
Ah, don't get angry, darling!
だってホントのことだもん
Because it's the truth, you see.
身体ばっかデカくなって 中身はガキだよね
Your body's grown big, but inside you're just a kid.
暴れないで doggie！
Don't rampage, doggie!
私 華奢な手だから
Because my hands are delicate...
リードなんて気まぐれで パッと落としちゃうかも
My leash might just slip off on a whim.
「だらしない！ 意気地ない！ ホント君は救えない！
So sloppy! No backbone! You're truly beyond saving!
堕落に耽っちゃって ご愁傷様
Indulging in depravity, my condolences.
夢がない！ 糧もない！ くせに愛は欲しいの？
No dreams! No sustenance! And yet you crave love?
なら3回まわって お手から…」
Then turn around three times and give me a paw..."
(ワン)
(Woof)
よく聞いて darling
Listen well, darling.
僻み妬み 人の企み この世は罠だらけ
Jealousy, envy, people's schemes, this world is full of traps.
ねえ ずっとここにいて？
Hey, will you stay here forever?
ひれ伏して doggie
Bow down, doggie.
どーせ誰も聴いてなんかないさ
Anyway, nobody is listening to it
音楽なんて全部ファッション
Music is all just fashion
音亡喰らって選手退場ワンナイ
Taking hits and getting kicked out, one-night
どーせ何も伝えてなんかないさ
Anyway, it's not conveying anything
なんとかトック撮って売名
Taking videos and name-dropping
あんな気取っておいて最低グンナイ
Acting all cool, it's the lowest, good night
どうしたってどう見たって 尊師達でもう大渋滞
Whatever you do, whatever you see, it's a big traffic jam with all these 'masters'
それでもあっち、こっち、そっち、ぼっち、卍、Zエイジ猿も欲しがる
Still, here, there, over there, alone, swastika, Z-age, even monkeys want it
パンチライン欲しいの
I want a punchline
意味とかどっちだっていいよ
It doesn't matter what the meaning is
歌詞とかどうでもいいので ノれるのください
I don't care about the lyrics, so give me something I can ride on
さぁ皆で笑いましょう
Come on, let's laugh together
芸術より数の大小？
Is it the size of the numbers rather than art?
ヴァイラスに酷い代償
A terrible price for the virus
じゃあどうすんの？それでいいんだっけ？
So what are you going to do? Is that really okay?
頭は空回り死んでいく
My head is spinning and I'm dying
Find myself instead...
ふざけるな！！！
Don't mess with me!
バイバイバズメロディ
Goodbye, buzz melody
疑えよ大概嘘ばかり
I'll doubt it, it's mostly just lies
化けんな幻想でも理想でも良い
Don't fake it, fantasy or ideal is fine
君の歌いたかった 物はどうしたんだい？
What was the thing you wanted to sing?
ぶざまでも オーライ嘘じゃない
Even if it's ugly, it's alright, it's not a lie
お金や擬奏で満たす前に
Before you fill it with money or fake
負けんな覚醒せよ鼓動達よ
Don't lose, awaken, my beating hearts
君の伝えたかった 物はどうしたんだい？
What was the thing you wanted to convey?
お書きになったそんな音楽は 現在使われておりません
The music you wrote is currently not in use
ポップソング、ヒットソング聴いて もう一度お書き直しください
Listen to pop songs, hit songs, please rewrite it once more
あーもうハイカラ作家 ばっか洒落臭いわはぁ...
Ah, another high-collar writer, it's all so pretentious... haa...
どいつもこいつもそいつもあいつも 意味わかんねぇ！！！
All of them, all of them, all of them, all of them, I don't understand!
どうしたってどう見たって 尊師達でもう大渋滞
Whatever you do, whatever you see, it's a big traffic jam with all these 'masters'
それでもあっち、こっち、そっち、ぼっち、卍、Zエイジ猿も欲しがる
Still, here, there, over there, alone, swastika, Z-age, even monkeys want it
パンチライン欲しいの
I want a punchline
意味とかどっちだっていいよ
It doesn't matter what the meaning is
歌詞とかどうでもいいので ノれるのください
I don't care about the lyrics, so give me something I can ride on
さぁ皆で祓いましょう
Come on, let's purify together
芸術より数なんでしょう？
Is it the size of the numbers rather than art?
ヴァイラスに酷い代償
A terrible price for the virus
じゃあどうすんの？それでいいんだっけ？
So what are you going to do? Is that really okay?
頭は空回り死んでいく
My head is spinning and I'm dying
Find myself instead...
ふざけるな！！！
Don't mess with me!
バイバイバズメロディ
Goodbye, buzz melody
疑えよ大概嘘ばかり
I'll doubt it, it's mostly just lies
化けんな幻想でも理想でも良い
Don't fake it, fantasy or ideal is fine
君の歌いたかった 物はどうしたんだい？
What was the thing you wanted to sing?
このままじゃ到底終われ
I can't end it like this
欲しいのはきっとお金じゃない
What I want is definitely not money
負けんな覚醒せよ鼓動達よ
Don't lose, awaken, my beating hearts
君の歌いたかった 物がきっとあるんだ
There must be something you wanted to sing
ふざけるな...
Don't mess with me...
ふざけるな！！！
Don't mess with me!
バイバイバズメロディ
Goodbye, buzz melody
疑えよ大概嘘ばかり
I'll doubt it, it's mostly just lies
化けんな幻想でも理想でも良い
Don't fake it, fantasy or ideal is fine
君の歌いたかった 物はどうしたんだい？
What was the thing you wanted to sing?
ぶざまでも オーライ嘘じゃない
Even if it's ugly, it's alright, it's not a lie
お金や擬奏で満たす前に
Before you fill it with money or fake
負けんな覚醒せよ鼓動達よ
Don't lose, awaken, my beating hearts
僕の伝えたかった 物はどうしたんだい？
What was the thing I wanted to convey?
意味わかんねぇ！！！
I don't understand!
意味わかんねぇ！
せーの！
Ready, set...
ふーちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Fu-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう！おめでとう！
Thank you! Congratulations!
やったー！おめでとう！
Hooray! Congratulations!
何才になったわけ？
How old are you now?
20才、バージョン２！
20 years old, version 2!
お若い！いいねー。お若いね。
So young! Nice. You're so young.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ちょっとみんな、せっかく来てくれ...
Wait everyone, since you came all this way...
あ！倒れた！ちょっと！あんたどうなってんのよ！
Ah! She fell! Hey! What's wrong with you!
何番のポーズそれ？はい、立ち上がって。
What pose number is that? Come on, stand up.
but, you're today's main star, Fu-chan!
じゃあちょっとみんなに一言言って、去ってもらおうかなって。
So, say a few words to everyone, and then they can leave.
一人ずつ来な、ほら、愛を、愛を言いに来な、ほら！
Come one by one, come on, come express your love, come on!
じゃあ、私から。
Okay, from me first.
うん、ママー！ / おめでとう！ありがとう！
Yeah, Mama! / Congratulations! Thank you!
おめでとう！ありがとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Thank you! Congratulations!
もうほら、ちゃんと来な、ほら！
Come on, come here properly, come on!
ちょっと変な人いて怖かったでちゅね。
There was a weird person, it was scary, wasn't it?
ママよ！ / 違うよ、違う、違う！
I'm Mama! / No, that's not it, that's wrong!
ほら、残りの二人も！
Come on, the remaining two as well!
ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って！
Wait a minute, wait a minute!
あの、別に芸能事務所、お笑いじゃないのよ、芸人じゃないのよ。
Um, we are not a comedy troupe, we are not comedians.
任せて、任せて！
Leave it to us, leave it to us!
はい、これからもお姉ちゃんに頼ってね！
Yes, continue to rely on your big sister!
お姉ちゃんだと思ってるの？本当に。おかし、おかしいよ。
Do you really think of yourself as a big sister? That's weird.
ほら、最後は、ちゃんと愛を！
Come on, show some love at the end!
愛を、愛を！ / でも、うち...
Love, love! / But, for me...
あのさ、すびびの仲やんか
Y'know, we're Subibi buddies, right?
そうね！だからせーのって言ったら何言うかわかるよな？
Right! So if I say 'ready, set...', you know what to say, right?
わかる！
I know!
いける？せーのでね、せーので。いくよ、せーの...
Let's do it on 'ready, set'. Ready...
スリー・フォー！
Three, four!
待って、なんで？なんでスリー・フォー？
Wait, why? Why 'three, four'?
スリー最高じゃない？
スリー最高やん！
Isn't it 'Three is the best'?
Yeah, 'Three is the best'!
せーの...
Ready, set...
スリー最高！
Three is the best!
はいポーズ！はいポーズ！
撮って撮って！
Pose! Pose!
Take a picture, take a picture!
オッケー？撮れた？
大丈夫？届いてる？
Did you get it?
Is it good? Is it reaching you?
オッケー、ありがとう！
Okay! Thank you!
ありがとう、みんな！ありがとー！
Thank you, everyone! Thank you!
がんばって！がんばって！
Good luck! Good luck!
ママ、ママ良かったよ！
ママ良かったよ！
Mama, Mama, you did great!
Mama did great!
ありがとうー！バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
みんなありがとう！バイバーイ！
Thank you, everyone! Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！がんばって！
Bye-bye! Good luck!
なんか、うるさかったな。
頑張るか。よし。
Man, they were noisy.
Time to do my best. Alright.
くだらない愛の結果で
As a result of a foolish love...
僕らは生まれ落ちて 呼吸さえしんどいな、って言っているけど
We were born into this world, complaining that even breathing is tough.
綺麗な言葉並べて 見にくさに蓋をして
Arranging pretty words, putting a lid on the ugliness,
自分を愛せないままだな
Still unable to love myself.
ずっと
Forever.
波に名前をつけること、僕らの呼吸に終わりがあること。
作詞・作曲：キタニタツヤ
[Song: Naming the Waves, That There Is an End to Our Breathing]
[Original Artist: Tatsuya Kitani]
くだらない嘘を言うたび 青い色こぼれ落ちた
Every time I tell a pointless lie, a blue color spills out,
ガラスの瞳が綺麗で
The glass eyes are so beautiful.
君のそのまぶたのように 優しい人になってさ
Becoming a kind person, just like your eyelids,
そんな僕を愛したいんだよ
I want to love myself like that.
私の 呼吸に 終わりが あること
That there is an end to my breathing...
君の声を覚えている
I remember your voice.
生まれては消えてゆくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born only to fade away, over and over again.
僕らがもし また会えたら なんて思ってた
I was thinking, "What if we could meet again?"
生まれては消えてゆくだけの 青白い波に名前を つけることに
Naming the pale blue waves that only rise and fall...
意味はなかったのかな なんてさ
Was it meaningless, I wonder?
他愛ない忙しさみたい 積み木で遊んでいる
Playing with building blocks like harmless busywork,
崩れるその日を待ってる
Waiting for the day it collapses.
澄み切った夜の静寂は 君の頬の赤色で
The clear night's silence is the red on your cheeks,
もうすぐ桜が咲くんだろう
Cherry blossoms will bloom very soon.
僕らの 呼吸に 意味がなくても
Even if there is no meaning to our breathing,
二人はまた恋をする
We will fall in love again.
生まれては消えてゆくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born only to fade away, over and over again.
そして君も 夜の海に 帰っていくんだろう
And you, too, will return to the night sea.
生まれては消えてゆくだけの 青白い波に名前を つけることに
Naming the pale blue waves that only rise and fall...
囚われている
I'm trapped by it.
ねえ 覚えているかな
Hey, do you remember?
いつかの春 of 朝に 桜の木の下で
On some spring morning, under the cherry blossom tree,
約束したこと
What we promised.
思い出も君の名前も いつしか失ってしまって保存
Someday losing both my memories and your name,
僕もいつか この海と一つになるんだろう
I, too, will eventually become one with this sea.
君のいない冬の空気が 僕の頬を刺すその痛みさえ
Even the pain of the winter air stinging my cheeks without you...
愛していたい
I want to love it.
生まれては消えてゆくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born only to fade away, over and over again.
僕らがもし また会えたら なんて思ってた
I was thinking, "What if we could meet again?"
生まれては消えてゆくだけの 青白い波に名前を つけることに
Naming the pale blue waves that only rise and fall...
意味はなかったのかな
Was it meaningless, I wonder?
こうして冬が終わって
As winter ends like this,
青い春が来る
A blue spring comes.
悩める人の子よ
Oh troubled child of man,
人ならざる者も
and even those who are not human,
先ずは目指せよ
first, set your sights...
生きているんだし
on being happy, since you are alive.
目を逸らした過去も
Both the past you averted your eyes from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future.
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counseling, oh dear me.
古今東西 ピースピース
All times and places, peace, peace.
UNHAPPY? UNLUCKY?
BE HAPPY!
UNDEAD
ねえねえねえ 何だかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, hey, why does it feel like I'm somehow fighting?
触れられない 過去の自分 自分 自分と
With my untouchable past self, self, self...
もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
Facing off against an invisible ghost that's already long dead.
幼気で痛い 記憶の奥
Innocent and painful, deep within my memories.
残念？もう居ないのに
What a pity? Even though they're no longer here.
あれ？そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Huh? You prefer that? How ironic.
透かされているのは 現在の自分？
Is the one being seen through my current self?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, this permanent label.
要はコンプレックス
Simply put, it's a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It feels like I'm possessed.
巻き付いたまま
Coiled tightly around me,
まだ離れない 在りし日の自分
it still won't let go, my past self from those days.
UNDEAD
死んじゃない お前とお前の連鎖
You're not dead, the chain between you and your past.
生きているということは 変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep on changing.
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Do not settle for unhappiness and be satisfied with it.
幸せになろうと しないなんてテロだ
Not even trying to be happy is an act of terror.
この世、この世は 奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
What will appear next, a demon or a serpent?
出会って 逢って やっと始まる物語
Meeting and clashing, the story finally begins.
さあ 人か化物か
Now, are you human or a monster?
古今東西 ピースピース
All times and places, peace, peace.
Past & future, can't change the past
Past & future, run for the future
なんだかどうして 未来になんぞ 何の期待も出来ないような気がして保存
For some reason, it feels like I can't expect anything from the future.
もう随分生きてる 既視感とテンプレで食傷
I've lived for quite a while, sick of the déjà vu and clichés.
素敵な出来事の 気配もない
There is no sign of any wonderful events.
残念
What a pity.
積んだ経験の因果 形骸化された神話 退屈な進化
The causality of accumulated experiences, a hollowed myth, a boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しい 飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
Simply put, I want stimulation, I'm bored, I've got used to it.
整っていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス
Well-ordered guidance, increasing compliance.
塞がれていくみたい 退屈して
It feels like I'm being shut in, bored out of my mind.
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
That, this, and all of them taste the exact same.
UNDEAD
死んじゃない お前とお前の連鎖
You're not dead, the chain between you and your past.
いずこの世も 過去も未来も 現在にあるんだ
In any era, both the past and the future exist in the present.
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Honestly fulfill the act of being alive.
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending!
UNDEAD
死んじゃない お前に言っているんだ
You're not dead, I'm talking to you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人であるなら
If you are a human, do not give up on being happy.
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
Just getting used to pain and enduring it...
死んでるも同然 屍のアンデッド
is virtually dead, a zombie of a corpse, undead.
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? Troublesome child of man.
UNLUCKY? 人ならざる者も
Unlucky? Even those who are not human.
BE HAPPY! 先ずは目指せよ保存
Be happy! First, set your sights...
生きているんだろ UNDEAD
You're alive, aren't you? Undead!
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Wallowing in unhappiness, or becoming happy,
そう全部全部 お前次第だ
yes, it's all, all up to you.
古今東西 森羅万象
All times and places, all creation.
ピースピース
Peace, peace.
Past & future, can't change the past
Past & future, run for the future
人の在るところに 常に憂い事
Where humans exist, there is always grief.
生き抜け 化物ばかりの物語
Survive this story full of monsters.
ちょこっとやんちゃで にこっと元気な
A little bit mischievous, and smiling with energy...
ちらっとスマイル アイドル
with a quick smile, an idol!
毎日をもっと 楽しくしたい
I want to make every day more fun...
貪欲アドベンチャー
A greedy adventure!
ひらひらスカートも ちゃんと着こなせるんだよ
I can wear a fluttering skirt quite well!
だからもっともっと 好きになってもいいよ
So it's okay to like me more and more.
一緒に 大空に飛び立とう
Let's take flight into the vast sky together!
光れ Starlight どんな輝きの中も
Shine, starlight, in any kind of brilliance.
強いきらめき 君に届いているかな
Is this strong sparkle reaching you, I wonder?
1ミリでも 伝わればいいな
Even if it's just one millimeter, I hope it reaches you.
チャージ チャレンジ 全開アクセル
Charge, challenge, full-throttle accelerator!
がんばる君へ
To you, who are doing your best,
一番乗りのスマイルを
I'll give you my first-place smile!
一番乗りのスマイルを贈るスバルch
Giving you the first smile on Subaru Channel!
Everyday night & day みんなで！
Everyday night & day, everyone together!
ブルーな気持ちにズバッと駆けつけ お助けしちゃうヒーロー！
A hero who rushes over to sweep away your blue feelings!
弱いハートじゃいられないから つよつよでいきましょう
Because we can't have a weak heart, let's go strong!
ハラハラなミズギで
With a heart-pounding swimsuit...
ドキドキのトキメキtime...？
is it a thrilling time...?
いつでもおいでよ
Come whenever you want,
一年中パラダイス
it's paradise all year round!
ドカンと曇り空吹き飛ばそう
Let's blow away the cloudy sky with a bang!
あがれ！スターマイン どんな暗闇の中も
Rise up! Star mine, even in the darkness...
眩しく照らす
shining brightly!
キキミに見つけてもらえた
Just because I was found by you,
それだけでもう運命なんだ
that alone is already destiny!
もっとずーーっと道は続いてく
The path will continue for a long, long time,
夢に向かって
towards our dream!
一緒に来てくれるかな？
Will you come along with me?
その手とって走れ
Take that hand and run!
つれていくよみんなで！
I'll take you, everyone together!
ささやく
Whispering...
恥ずかしいけれど包装
is embarrassing, but...
伝えたい想い
I want to convey my feelings,
今なら言える
I can say it now.
キミのエールがチカラになるよ
Your support becomes my strength!
いつも元気を分けてくれて...
Always sharing your energy with me,
頑張っていけるんだ
I can keep doing my best,
笑って過ごせるんだ包装
I can spend my time laughing.
ホントに
Truly...
ありがとうの気持ちを
with a feeling of gratitude!
歌え！starlight どんな輝きの中も
Sing! Starlight, in any kind of radiance,
強いキラメキ
a strong sparkle!
キミに届いているかな？
I wonder if it reaches you?
1ミリでも伝われfight oh！
Even if it's just 1 millimeter, let it be conveyed, fight, oh!
もっとずーーっと道は続いてく
The path will continue for a long, long time,
夢に向かって夢を
towards our dream!
一緒に来てくれるかな？
Will you come along with me?
その手とって走れ
Take that hand and run!
つれていくよみんなで！包装
I'll take you, everyone together!
キミと駆けるスバル！
Running with you, Subaru!
スパチャありがとうございました！後半に続きます！
Thank you for the Super Chats! We'll continue in the second half!
ルーナ頑張れー！
Go for it, Luna!
お誕生日おめでとうー！
Happy Birthday!
誰かのための痛み？
A pain for someone?
僕の願い、やがて散り散り
My wishes will soon be scattered.
椅子取りゲームみたい
It's like a game of musical chairs.
それでも、息をしていくしかない
Even so, I have no choice but to keep breathing.
まだ、聞こえるか？
Can you still hear it?
とっくのとうに詰まった呼吸
My breath, which was blocked long ago.
関係ない、うるせえわ
It doesn't matter, shut up.
自分だけが聞こえている
Only I can hear myself.
安定なんて捨てた
I've abandoned stability.
もう、すべてを振り切るスピードで
With a speed that throws everything away,
その瞬間まで、足掻いて
struggling until that moment.
ただ、脳絞って今、見えるとこまで
Just squeezing my brain until I can see it now.
この瞬間を飲み干して、また踊って
Drinking this moment dry and dancing again,
見たことないもの、見せて
show me something I've never seen before!
「君の代わりはいない」
"There's no substitute for you."
もし、誰かが否定しても包装
Even if someone denies it,
僕の代わりはいない
there's no substitute for me.
違うことない、僕の目覚まし
My alarm clock that won't ring wrongly.
誰かの祈る手を払った痛み
The pain of brushing aside someone's prayerful hands.
どこから漂う悪意の兆し
Signs of malice drifting from somewhere.
正しさに息を潜めた怒り
Anger that held its breath under righteousness.
それすらも僕に残った光
Even that is the light left in me.
誰彼の熱を奪う感覚
The sensation of stealing someone's heat.
逃げる気はとうにないぜ、全く
I have no intention of running away at all.
この手が震えるほどの錯覚が、起こした摩擦
The friction caused by the illusion that makes these hands tremble.
まだ、見えてるか？
Can you still see it?
とっくにスポットライトを奪った包装
I've already taken the spotlight.
関係ない、うるせえわ
It doesn't matter, shut up.
自分だけに聞かせてる包装
Letting only myself hear it.
安定なんてやめだ包装
I stop stability.
もう、すべてを振り切るスピードで包装
With a speed that throws everything away,
この瞬間だけ、足掻いたって意味ないぜ包装
it's meaningless to struggle just for this moment.
さあ この瞬間を飲み干して
Come on, drink up this moment
また踊って
and dance again
尖った生意気もの見せて
show me something sharp and cheeky
連れていかれるように
As if being led away
踏み出した暗い街へ
I stepped out into the dark streets
tell me what you need
後追う背中は黒く染まってた
The back I followed was stained black
hold up
悪党？それとも正義？ huh?
A villain? Or justice? Huh?
やりがい searching 馬鹿みたい流通
Searching for a purpose, like a fool
目の前の問題は it's too much now流通
The problem in front of me is too much now
後回しでもまあ良いじゃん
Even if I put it off, it's fine, right?
人生の意味 結局何？
What's the meaning of life anyway?
不安定な日々に裏返る声
My voice cracks in these unstable days
あれこれ言ってる間に
While saying this and that
姿を消し去った君は誰？流通
Who are you, who disappeared?
曖昧な世界が変わった
The ambiguous world changed
あの日と
On that day...
ど派手に響かせた声がまだ今も鳴り止まない
The voice that echoed loudly still hasn't stopped ringing even now
紅の夜に心奪われて流通
My heart was stolen by the crimson night
このどうしようもない感情に君を映してた流通
I reflected you in this helpless feeling
連れてく手を置いて流通
Leave the hand that leads you
気づけば遠い街で流通
Before I knew it, in a distant city
引き返し元通りなるのにはもう遅かった流通
It was already too late to turn back and go back to normal流通
wait hold up now流通
Wait, hold up now
sos 逃げ道がないの流通
SOS, there's no way out流通
え、ちょまって how is it my fault?流通
Eh, wait up, how is it my fault?流通
レフト、ライトステップからの流通
From left, right step...流通
get down に見せかけて clap流通
pretending to get down, then clap流通
からかっといて立場は対等？流通
You tease me and then say our standing is equal?流通
助けてやって何その態度流通
I help you out, and what's with that attitude?流通
不満のなかだって生まれる一生流通
An entire life born out of frustration流通
垣間見えるのは愛流通
What's briefly visible is love流通
また淡々と取り繕っている
Once again, indifferently keeping up appearances,
本当の顔は誰のため？
for whose sake is my real face?
だんだん苦しくなるね保存
It's gradually becoming painful, isn't it?
お揃いの前の前の前の前
Before, before, before we matched...
ただ泣いてないで笑っていたいよ
I don't want to just cry, I want to laugh.
All eyes on me いつまでも free forever
All eyes on me, forever free forever...
愛なんて分かっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand love at all.
All eyes on me いつの日か Deep Faker
All eyes on me, someday a Deep Faker.
脱いでみて
Try stripping it off,
演技でも何でもなら
even if it's acting or anything,
それならいっそ剥ぎ取って
if so, I'd rather tear it away.
胸に秘めているディープフェイカー保存
The Deep Faker hidden in my chest.
もう泣いたように笑っていたんだ
I was already laughing as if I had cried.
All eyes on me 偽りのディープフェイカー
All eyes on me, the false Deep Faker.
愛なんて分かっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand love at all.
All eyes on me いつの間にかディープフェイカー
All eyes on me, before I knew it, a Deep Faker.
All eyes, all eyes on me, me, me, free
All eyes, all eyes on me, Deep Faker保存
All eyes, all eyes on me, Deep Faker
All eyes, all eyes on me, me, me, free
All eyes, all eyes on me, Deep Faker保存
All eyes, all eyes on me, Deep Faker
ふぅ、みんな、どうでしたか？
Whew... Everyone, how was that?
いや、今回はですね、あのハウスにね、初めて挑戦したんですけれども
Well, this time, I took on the challenge of house style for the first time,
あの、2ヶ月で、あの詰め込んで、踊れてましたか？
cramming it all in just two months. Was I able to dance it?
いや、めっちゃ頑張ったってコメントが書いてくれてるんだろうなぁ、へへ。
Man, I bet there are comments saying 'you worked so hard,' hehe.
でね、あの「波に名前をつけること」「僕らの呼吸に終わりがあること」って曲では
And during the songs "Naming the Waves" and "Our Breath Has an End",
リフトをしたり、あの、クルクルね、回って。あれも初めてやりました。
we did lifts and spun around in circles. That was my first time doing that too.
踊れてたら嬉しいね！
I hope I managed to dance it well!
いや、ゲストのね、博衣こより先輩、天音かなた先輩とも一緒に踊って
Also, I danced with the guests, Hakui Koyori-senpai and Amane Kanata-senpai,
スバル先輩とは、憧れのスバル先輩と2人っきりでドキドキタイムもしちゃったり
and I had a heart-pounding moment alone with the Subaru-senpai I look up to!
ロザ先輩とアキロゼ先輩となでちゃんとは、もう対決しまくって
I had non-stop face-offs with Roza-senpai, Aki Rose-senpai, and Nade-chan,
ロゼ先輩とマリンちゃんはカプで、フブキちゃんとはかっこよく、いや〜
did a couple-like performance with Rose-senpai and Marine-chan, and looked cool with Fubuki-chan!
ゲストパートもたくさんね、素晴らしいのがあったんじゃないでしょうか！
There were so many wonderful guest parts, weren't there?
ということで、皆さん、何か忘れてませんか？
And so, everyone... aren't you forgetting something?
ね、皆さん、ちょっと水見の休憩タイムもね、もうそろそろ終わらないといけない。
Right, everyone? Mizumi's break time has to end pretty soon.
よし、立つか！
Alright, let's stand up!
はい、ということで、なんとですね、こんな感じで言うのも何なんですが、
Okay, so! It feels a bit casual to announce it like this, but...
新曲が出ます！イェーイ！
My new song is coming out! Yay!
初のオリジナル楽曲！ふふふ。やばい、体が疲れた、よいしょ、よいしょ。
My very first original song! Hehehe. Oh no, my body is tired. Up we go...
はい、ということで、えっと、作詞・作曲・編曲はナトダニユーさんに作ってもらいました！
So, yes! The lyrics, composition, and arrangement were done by Natodaniyu-san!
ありがと、どんどパフパフ、どんどパフパフ！
Thank you! *drumroll and horns blowing*
はい、このあとすぐMV公開がね、この配信が終わったあとあるのですが、リダイレクトで飛びます。
Right after this stream ends, the MV will be released, and you'll be redirected to it.
そしてデジタルリリースは、今日の0時からなので、たくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです！
The digital release starts at midnight tonight, so I hope you listen to it a lot!
じゃあ、ちょっと早速なんですけれども、その新曲をお披露目しちゃおうかな？
Now, without further ado, should I perform this new song for you?
いや、どんな楽曲なんだろう、気になるな。どんな楽曲なんだろう。いきます！
I wonder what kind of song it is? I'm so curious! Here we go!
うみゃうにゃ　うみゃうにゃ
Umyau-nya, umyau-nya
うみゃうにゃ　うみゃうにゃ保存
くるるん　くるるん
Kururun, kururun
あー　そろそろごはんの時間かな
Ah, is it almost mealtime?
あ　でもでも　やっぱやっぱ
Ah, but but, still still...
家から一歩も出たくないっ
I don't want to take a single step out of the house!
こんな時はそうだ！
In times like this, that's right!
デリのの音が
the sound of delivery
「説明しよう！極限までお腹を空かし美味しくいただくのだ！」
Let me explain! To starve myself to the limit, then eat deliciously!
めんどいめんどいマジめんどいわ
Troublesome, troublesome, seriously troublesome
けっきょくぐだぐだ時間溶けたわ
In the end, time melted away while idling
ぴろりんぴろりん5回目アラーム
Beep beep, beep beep, 5th alarm
コンビニいこー
Let's go to the convenience store!
わちゃわちゃはちゃめちゃ奇想天外
Cluttered, chaotic, unpredictable
ドタバタてんやわんや見逃せない
Hectic, topsy-turvy, can't miss it!
ピンチだってちょちょいのちょいで
Even in a pinch, in a jiffy,
てやっ！てやっ！そりゃっ！そりゃっ！
Te-ya! Te-ya! So-rya! So-rya!
万事解決☆
Everything's resolved!
うみゃうにゃ うみゃうにゃ おいしくなーれ
Umyau-nya, umyau-nya, become delicious!
あれもこれも全部 食べたいな保存
I want to eat this, that, and everything!
ぱくぱく うみゃうにゃ ハピネス ライフ
Munching, umyau-nya, happy life!
食べて 寝て 遊んで また食べる！
Eat, sleep, play, and eat again!
ペコペコ ペコペコ はらぺこちょ
Starving, starving, super hungry!
うみゃうにゃ うみゃうにゃ 食いつくせー！
Umyau-nya, umyau-nya, eat up everything!
はーい！
Hi!
おー、いい天気！
Wow, nice weather!
あの雲ソフトクリームみたい！
That cloud looks like soft-serve ice cream!
あ、あっちわ！わたがし！
Ah, over there is cotton candy!
雲ってふわふわで美味しそう...
Clouds look fluffy and delicious...
人生で1回は食べてみたいよね～
I want to eat them at least once in my life~
うじゃじゃない！！
No, wait, that's not it!!
しんどいしんどいまじしんどいわ
It's tough, it's tough, it's seriously tough
現実逃避なんどもしちゃうわ
I escape reality over and over again
妄想 空想 頭が暴走
Delusions, fantasies, my head is running wild
カツオ食べたーい！！
I want to eat bonito!!
だらだらだらだら 怠惰全開
Lazing around, full on lazy
ネガティブ思考もご愛嬌です！
Even negative thoughts are charming!
世界ってぽいのぽいのぽいで
The world is just toss, toss, toss
えいやっ えいやっ とりゃっ とりゃっ ねじ伏せちゃうぞ☆
Eiya, eiya, torya, torya, I'll twist it down!☆
うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ お腹空いたら
Umyau, umyau, umyau, umyau, when I'm hungry
突撃 隣の晩御飯決（ちょーやばい！）
Invading my neighbor's dinner
ぱくぱく うみゃうみゃ しあわせタイム
Munch munch, umyau umyau, happiness time
お、食欲で生きてます
Oh, I live by my appetite
だからどうかお願い
So please, I beg of you
このお腹を満たして神様！
Fill this stomach, oh dear God!
たべたい！
I want to eat!
ねてたい！
I want to sleep!
難しいことは何も考えたくない
I don't want to think about anything difficult
あとあと、みんなでお菓子パーティーもしよー！！
And also, let's have a sweets party together with everyone!!
うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ おいしくなぁれ
Umyau, umyau, umyau, umyau, become delicious
あれもこれでも全部食べたいな
I want to eat this and that, all of it
ぱくぱく うみゃうみゃ ハピネスライフ
Munch munch, umyau umyau, happy life
食べて寝て遊んでまた食べて
Eat, sleep, play, and eat again
ペコペコペコペコ 腹ペコだぁ
Peko peko peko peko, I'm starving
うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ おかわりください
Umyau, umyau, umyau, umyau, seconds, please
ひとまずご飯をお腹いっぱい
For now, fill my stomach with food
食べさせて！
Let me eat!
まだ足りない もっともっと
I haven't had enough yet, more, more
食べさせてーー！
Let me eat more!
新曲どうだったー？
How was the new song?
お家に、お呼ばれしちゃったみんながね、ちょっと距離近めでね、
You guys got invited to my house, and we're super close...
ASMRボイスが、ちょっとこんな感じで、
and the ASMR voice is kind of like this...
まあ、ちょっと適当なんですけど、まあそんな感じのボイスになっております。
Well, it's a bit random, but that's the kind of voice it is!
こちら、数量限定じゃない！
This is NOT limited in quantity!
ので、焦らずにみんなゆっくりで大丈夫です！
So there's no need to rush, take your time!
グッズは22時10…ん？
Merchandise starts selling at 22:10... wait?
22時10分から販売開始です！
Sales start at 22:10!
直筆のサインとかもね、全部、もう何もかも数量限定じゃないので、
Hand-written signatures and everything else are not limited in quantity,
あのすうちゃんのサインも、あの付いてきますのでね、フルセットを買ったら。
Su-chan's signature is included if you buy the full set.
皆さん、よろしくお願いします、ぜひ！
Everyone, please support me! Definitely!
買ってね！
Please buy it!
いっぱい買ってね！
Buy a lot of them!
はい、ということで、以上、ミニみあによるグッズ紹介でした！
All right, so that was the merchandise introduction by Mini-Mia!
はーい、ということで、ミニみあありがとう！
Yeees, so, thank you, Mini-Mia!
なんか結構ミスってたな。まあ、ミニみあだからね。
She messed up quite a bit, didn't she? Well, she is Mini-Mia.
まあすうじゃないから。まあ仕方ないか。仕方ないか。
She's not Su, after all. So I guess it can't be helped!
ということで、誕生日の3Dライブはどうだったでしょうか？
So, how did you like my birthday 3D live?
憧れのぶいすぽに入ってから、みんなにいーっぱい応援してもらって、ここまで来れました。
Since joining my dream group Vspo, I've received so much support from everyone, which got me here.
みんなに少しでもね、かっこよかったとか、
If even a little bit, you thought I was cool or...
すうのこと応援しててよかったって思ってもらえてると、とっても嬉しいです！
...felt glad that you supported Su, I would be so incredibly happy!
MVはこのあとすぐ公開で、リダイレクトで飛ぶので、
The MV will be released right after this and you'll be redirected,
チャンネルはそのままでよろしくお願いします！
so please stay on the channel!
ということで、みんな、これからもよろしくね！ありがとう！
So, everyone, please keep supporting me! Thank you!
じゃあ、ばいばーい！まったねー！
Well then, bye-bye! See you later!
すうりすへ
ずっとまっててくれてありがとう
[On-screen letter]
To the Su-Squirrels,
Thank you for waiting for me for so long.
このすうがどんなにささえられてるか
わかるかなあ
[On-screen letter]
I wonder if you know how much
I, Su, am supported? Do you know?
じまんのすうになるよ
これからもしんらいしてね たのしんでね
[On-screen letter]
I will become a Su that you can be proud of.
Please trust me from now on too, and enjoy the journey.
すうががんばれるのは
すうりすのおかげ！！
[On-screen letter]
The reason Su can do her best
is thanks to you, Su-Squirrels!!